<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walker Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Walker Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ARW</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover article!</title>
      <link>/posts/third_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/third_post/</guid>
      <description>An article from my postdoctoral research was recently featured as a supplemental cover to J. Phys Chem B!
Check it out here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D proteins in real life!</title>
      <link>/posts/second_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/second_post/</guid>
      <description>If you have a mobile phone, you can play with some WalkerLab proteins in real life, courtesy of Sukolsak Sakshuwong and Umberto Raucci.
Go here and type the molecule name of your choice! Alternatively, the following QR codes will display specific proteins relevant to our proposed research. Open up your mobile phone camera app and hover it over the following images; it will ask if you would like to follow a link to display the image interactively on your phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s go WalkerLab</title>
      <link>/posts/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon to a university near you, if you live in the Detroit area. :)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classes/</guid>
      <description>#Basics
Getting started with python: https://py.checkio.org/ https://www.learnpython.org/
Getting started with conda: https://conda.io/projects/conda/en/latest/user-guide/getting-started.html
Github basics: https://guides.github.com/activities/hello-world/
#Scientific programming
Intro to scientific python: https://stanford.edu/~schmit/cme193/lectures.html
Using numpy: https://cs231n.github.io/python-numpy-tutorial/
#Machine learning
Pandas dataframes: https://github.com/jvns/pandas-cookbook (Has online version to test without installing) https://www.activestate.com/blog/how-to-clean-machine-learning-datasets-using-pandas/
Pytorch basics: https://pytorch.org/tutorials/
Keras/Tensorflow basics: https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials https://keras.io/guides/
#Quantum chemistry
http://vergil.chemistry.gatech.edu/notes/
#Useful utilities
https://automeris.io/WebPlotDigitizer/
 Classes I plan to teach a course on photochemistry in biology! Here is a set of topics:
  Basics of photochemistry and excited state theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Alice R. Walker
Stanford Chemistry
SLAC PULSE Institute
333 Campus Dr.
Stanford, CA 94305
ll Email: &amp;amp; arwalker@stanford.edu
Websites: &amp;amp; Google Scholar, ResearchGate
Education  March 2018 Ph.D. in Physical Chemistry, University of North Texas Dissertation: Computational Simulations of Cancer and Disease-Related Enzymatic Systems using Molecular Dynamics and Combined Quantum Methods September 2013-August 2016 Ph.D. Candidate in Physical Chemistry, Wayne State University May 2011 B.S. in Chemistry with distinction, University of Michigan-Dearborn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/jobopenings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jobopenings/</guid>
      <description>Job Openings We are not currently hiring for postdoctoral positions, but watch this space! Applicants interesting in pursuing external support are welcome. PhD and undergraduate students interested in research opportunities are also very welcome.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to work on excited state simulations of biomolecules, relevant method development, and or the development of new machine learning models, please contant arwalker[at]wayne[dot]edu for further information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/old/</guid>
      <description>#Wiki
{{if and (gt .WordCount 100 ) (.Params.toc) }}
{{.Title}}{{ .TableOfContents }}{{end}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/</guid>
      <description>People PI: Alice R. Walker CV Google ScholarResearch GateOrcIDTwitterHobbies: knitting, video games, staring at screensUndergraduate Researcher: Ashlyn Murphy CVPostdoctoral Researcher: Nina McCulley CV--!Graduate Student: Solomon Yamoah Effah CV --!Graduate Student: Vishaka Pathiranage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications Alice R. Walker, Boning Wu, Jan Meisner, Michael D. Fayer, and Todd J. Martínez. Proton transfer from a photoacid to a water wire: first principles simulations and fast fluorescence spectroscopy. J. Phys. Chem. B 2021, 125, 45, 12539–12551 https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c07254 Featured on supplementary cover. https://pubs.acs.org/toc/jpcbfk/125/45 Madison B. Berger, Alice R. Walker, Erik Antonio Vázquez-Montelongo and G. Andrés Cisneros. Computational investigations of two iron and a-ketoglutarate-dependent family enzymes: structural and electronic level insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Overview In the Walker group, we are interested in how to connect biological phenomena and measurements of fluorescence using computational chemistry. Molecular modeling provides ways of translating between what we see in experiment, usually a signal or set of signals, to atomic or electronic level details of the system. To investigate fluorescence in biological systems, we use and develop new techniques in quantum chemistry, molecular dynamics, and excited state simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/wiki/</guid>
      <description>#Wiki
Work in progress :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>